AKINLOLU OGUNLEYE (Software Engineer)

I am a full stack software engineer that is agile. I have about two years experience of writing clean code in Javascript and Typescript. I have a practical knowledge of test-driven development. I am passionate about using web technologies to build amazing products to meet client needs. I also have experience using Docker and foundational knowledge of AWS cloud services

Sangotedo, Ajah, Lagos **08142615437**

akinlolu.ogunleye@de cagon.dev

<u>github</u>

EXPERIENCE

DECAGON, Lagos, Nigeria — Software Engineer

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

I created secured REST APIs in Javascript and Typescript using Express. I have written unit and functional tests for the APIs.
I also handled databases such as PostgreSQL and MongoDB
I also worked built containers for web applications with Docker

MENTOR WITHOUT BORDERS, Bucharest,Romania — *FrontEnd Developer(Mentee)*

August 2020 - November 2020

I learnt the fundamentals of frontend development using vanilla javascript and React

I also created frontend applications using React such as a todo-app and a calculator

EDUCATION

OBAFEMI AWOLOWO UNIVERSITY, Ile-ife, Osun state — *Mechanical Engineering*

JULY 2014 - JULY 2019

Alongside a team of young engineers, we created an evaporative cooling system with a peteir module. I also worked on how to increase the effectiveness of the blades of a rotary lawn mower.

PROJECTS

WeaOr

I created a progressive web application (PWA) with vanilla javascript that gets the weather condition of any city and returns it to the user's screen in a styled format.

I learnt how to use the fetch API, service worker and firebase hosting while creating this project.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT,

BOOTSTRAP, MATERIAL-UI

REACT JS,

NODEJS

EXPRESS

MONGODB, POSTGRESQL

DOCKER

ASSETS

I possess good communication skills.

I have a good team work spirit and great adaptability.

I have practical knowledge of Agile leadership

MOVIECLASH: movie fight

November 2020

This is an application that compares two movies based on their imdb rating, awards, revenue generated. I used the OMDb API to create this application. I also used the bulma css frame work for the styling. I also learnt to use the axios library for the API call. I also learnt more about rendering HTML elements dynamically in JAVASCRIPT

DECABLOG: decablog

May 2021

A full stack web application that allows creative minds to share ideas in written form. We used React, Material-UI, React-Router to build the frontend.